Kuldeep S. Kulkarni

kkulkar1@asu.edu kuldeepkulkarni.github.io +91-7676756467

Summary

During my PhD, I proposed deep learning based, fast, data-driven solutions to inverse problems like compressive image and light-field reconstructions, the first of their kind, as well as novel solutions to reconstruction-free computer vision from computational imagers. During my internship stints, I have worked on action detection in videos using bi-directional LSTMs and weakly supervised problems like joint localization of multiple concepts like action, object and person. I was one of the 30 graduating students selected to participate at the CVPR 2017 Doctoral Consortium, and have won the best paper award at CVPR CCD workshop 2015. A track record of mentoring masters and PhD students for the past 5 years, and have been involved in writing grants during my PhD. I have played key roles in successful cross-university collaborations with labs from CMU, Cornell University, University of Arizona and University of Maryland. Currently, I am working on image and video generation problems using generative adversarial networks (GANs).

Employment

Research Scientist at Adobe Research, Bengaluru (Mar 2019- present)

Post-doctoral Researcher at Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh (August 2017- Feb 2019) Advisor: Aswin Sankaranarayanan

Education

- PhD in Electrical Engineering with Arts, Media and Engg. (AME) concentration (Fall 2012
 Summer 2017)
 - Arizona State University, Tempe
- Master of Science in Electrical Engineering with Signal Processing and Communication as specialization (Fall 2010 - Summer 2012)
 Arizona State University, Tempe
- Bachelor of Technology in Electrical and Electronics Engg. (2005-2009) National Institute of Technology Karnataka, Surathkal, India.

Publications, Book Chapters and Patents

- Michael Jones, Tim Marks, Kuldeep Kulkarni, Method and System for Detecting Actions in Videos using Contour Sequences, US Patent App. 15/670,021, 2019
- Suhas Lohit, Rajhans Singh, **Kuldeep Kulkarni**, Pavan Turaga, Rank-Regularized Measurement Operators for Compressive Imaging, Asilomar Conference, 2019
- Kuldeep Kulkarni, Pavan Turaga, Anuj Srivastava, Rama Chellappa, Pattern Recognition, Wiley Encyclopedia on Electrical and Electronics Engineering.
- Kuldeep Kulkarni, Suhas Lohit, Pavan Turaga, Ronan Kerviche, Amit Ashok,
 'ReconNet: Non-Iterative Reconstruction of Images from Compressively Sensed Measurements', IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) 2016 [citations: 175].
- Suhas Lohit, Kuldeep Kulkarni, Ronan Kerviche, Pavan Turaga, Amit Ashok,
 'Convolutional Neural Networks for Non-iterative Reconstruction of Compressively Sensed Images', IEEE Transactions on Computational Imaging, 2018
- Kuldeep Kulkarni, Pavan Turaga, 'Reconstruction-Free Action Inference from compressive imagers', IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence, 2016.
- Kuldeep Kulkarni, Pavan Turaga,
 'Fast integral image estimation at 1% measurement rate', under revisions at IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence.

- Sohil Shah, Kuldeep Kulkarni, Arijit Biswas, Ankit Gandhi, Om Deshmukh, Larry Davis, 'Weakly Supervised Learning of Heterogeneous Concepts in Videos', European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV) 2016¹.
- Suhas Lohit, **Kuldeep Kulkarni**, Pavan Turaga, Jian Wang, Aswin Sankaranarayanan 'Reconstruction-free Inference on Compressive Measurements', at the **4th IEEE Workshop on Computational Cameras and Displays (CCD)**, held in conjunction with IEEE CVPR, 2015. (**Best Paper Award**)
- Mayank Gupta*, Arjun Jauhari*, Kuldeep Kulkarni, Suren Jayasuriya, Alyosha Molnar, Pavan Turaga, 'Compressive Light Field Reconstruction using Deep Learning', at CVPR 2017 CCD workshop
- Suhas Lohit, Kuldeep Kulkarni, Pavan Turaga,
 'Direct Inference on Compressive Measurements using Convolutional Neural Networks', International Conference on Image Processing, 2016
- P8: Kuldeep Kulkarni, Pavan Turaga,
 'Recurrence Textures for Activity Recognition from compressive cameras', International Conference on Image Processing, 2012.
- Ankit Gandhi, Arijit Biswas, Om Deshmukh, Sohil Shah, Kuldeep Kulkarni, Method and System for Multimedia Processing to Identify Concepts in Multimedia, patent application submitted to USPTO.
- Li-Chi Huang, Kuldeep Kulkarni, Pavan Turaga, Anik Jha, Suhas Lohit, Suren Jayasuriya, Pavan Turaga, CS-VQA: Visual Question Answering with Compressively Sensed Images, ICIP 2018.

Mentoring Experience

I have mentored the following masters and PhD students.

- Suhas Lohit His master's thesis work was awarded the 'Best Paper Award' at 4th IEEE
 Workshop on Computational Cameras and Displays (CCD), held in conjunction with
 CVPR 2015. Currently, PhD student at ASU.
- Mayank Gupta His master's thesis work on compressive light-field reconstruction using deep learning was presented at the CVPR 2017 CCD workshop. Currently at Meta Co, San Mateo, CA
- Li-Chi Huang His master's thesis work on compressive-VQA was accepted at ICIP 2018. Currently at Graftek Imaging.
- Tejas Gokhale at CMU, currently PhD student at ASU.

Prior Work Experience

- Research Intern at Mitsubishi Electric Research Labs (MERL), Cambridge, MA (May-Sep 2016). Action detection in videos using computationally efficient contour image features and multi-scale, bi-directional LSTMs. A patent application based on this work has been filed. Host: Mike Jones
- Research Intern at Xerox Research Centre India, Bengaluru, India (May-Aug 2015). Worked on joint spatio-temporal localization of multiple concepts like ({object,action},{subject,action}) in weakly-labeled youtube videos, leading to a paper at ECCV 2016.
- Research Intern at Bausch & Lomb, Rochester, NY (May-Aug 2013). Applied image processing techniques for segmentation of OCT images of contact lens.
- **Project Assistant**: Dept. of Instrumentation Engg and Applied Physics, Indian Institute of Science, (July 2009- March 2010)
- Summer Intern: Dept. of Electrical Engg., Indian Institute of Science, (May 2008-June 2008). Applied shape-context feature descriptor for online hand-writing recognition of two South-Indian languages, Kannada and Tamil.

References

Available upon request.

¹CVPR and ECCV are highly selective computer vision conferences with acceptance rates of around 25%, similar to top journals like TPAMI, which has a impact factor of 5.781.